Guide to the Library Newsletters, Acquisitions, and Accessions List, 1899-1986 UA.08.01.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Library newsletters, acquisitions, and accessions list
1899-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Library
UA.08.01.0005
30.7 Linear Feet
Includes newsletters created by the library for Duke University faculty announcing new acquisitions and library news, as well as accession books, collection acquisition information, statistics, bookplates, and other materials.
Provenance
The Library Newsletters and Accessions Lists were received in multiple accessions, various dates. Accession 2015.0001 received December, 2014.
Collection Overview
Includes newsletters created by the library for Duke University faculty announcing new acquisitions and library news, as well as accession books, collection acquisition information, statistics, bookplates, and other materials.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisitions (Libraries); Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University. Library
- General Library Bulletin, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
- Duke University Library Faculty News Letter, 1940-1943 (Box 1)
- Pamphlet Accession List, 1940-1943, 1945 (Box 1)
- Accessions to the University Library, 1941-1942, 1944-1946, nos. 1-132 (5 folders) (Box 1)
- Accessions to the University Library, 1946-1949, nos. 133-196; issues from February to June, 1949 unnumbered; starting with no. 155, occasional "News and Accessions" newsletter included (6 folders) (Box 2)
- Duke University Library Newsletter, 1953-1959 (2 folders) (Box 2)
- Duke University Library Newsletter, 1959-1986 (5 folders) (Box 3)
- Current Legal Publications, Law Library, 1947-1948 (Box 3)
- College of Engineering, Library Review, 1965-1978 (Box 3)
- Pamphlet Accessions (P181-1598), 1899-1900 (Box 4)
- Pamphlet Accessions (P1599-3131), 1901-1902 (Box 4)
- Pamphlet Accessions (P3132-4750), 1902-1905 (Box 4)
- Pamphlet Accessions (P4751-8813), 1905-1908 (Box 4)
- Pamphlet Accessions (P8814-12,300), 1908-1916 (Box 4)
- Pamphlet Accessions (P12,301-17,300), 1916-1925 (Box 4)
- Pamphlet Accessions (P17,301-22,300), 1925-1930 (Box 5)
- Pamphlet Accessions (P22,301-72,511), 1930-1940 (Box 5)
- Acquisition, Lanson library, 1927 (Box 6)
- Lanson Collection, A-E (Box 6)
- Lanson Collection, Faber-Mathis (Box 6)
- Lanson Collection, Mathos-T (Box 6)
- Lanson Collection, U-Z, Supplements, Brochures (Box 6)
- Composition books (Box 6)
- This box contains the files of University Librarian William Boyd regarding the Richmond Bond Collection (which the Library did not acquire). Included are Boyd's Memorandum Regarding a Library and his description of Bibliotecha Parsoniana, 1932. (Box 7)
- Donors to the Libraries, 1939-1942 (Box 8)
- Building a Library Collection of Material on Government in Metropolitan Areas and Related Local Problems, a report to the Librarian and Political Science Committee, 1959 (Box 8)
- Latin-American Library Project (Box 8)
- South Asian Studies (Box 8)
- Southern Americana Collection (Box 8)
- Special Book Funds (Box 8)
- Thomas, James Augustus, correspondence with librarian, 1928-1931 (Box 8)
- Thomas, James Augustus, correspondence with librarian, 1935 April-1936 Feb. (Box 8)
- Thomas, James Augustus, correspondence with librarian, 1936 March-1937 June (Box 8)
- Utopia Collection (Box 8)
- Acquisitions, gift records (microfilm), 1931-1959 (Box 9)
- Cataloging Dept. statistics, 1914-1935 (Box 9)
- Accession Books, 1-5000, 5001-7000, 7001-9000 (Box 10)
- Accession Books, 9001-11,000; 11,001-13,000; 13,001-15,000 (Box 11)
- Accession Books, 15,001-20,000; 20,001-25,000 (Box 12)
- Accession Books, 25,001-30,000; 30,001-35,000 (Box 13)
- Accession Books, 35,001-40,000; 40,001-45,000; 45,001-50,000 (Box 14)
- Accession Books, 50,001-55,000; 55,001-60,000; 60,001-65,000 (Box 15)
- Accession Books, 65,001-70,000; 70,001-75,000; 75,000-80,000 (Box 16)
- Accession Books, 80,001-85,000; 85,001-90,000; 90,001-95,000 (Box 17)
- Accession Books, 95,001-100,000; 100,001-105,000; 105,001-110,000 (Box 18)
- Accession Books, 110,001-115,000; 115,001-120,000; 120,001-125,000 (Box 19)
- Accession Books, 125,001-130,000; 130,001-135,000; 135,001-140,000 (Box 20)
- Accession Books, 140,001-145,000; 145,001-150,000; 150,001-155,000 (Box 21)
- Accession Books, 155,001-160,000; 160,001-165,000; 165,001-170,000 (Box 22)
- Accession Books, 170,001-175,000; 175,001-637,172 (Box 23)
- Ledger: Broadsides, maps and music, 1938-1947 (Box 24)
- Ledger, Library of Congress Card Account, 1941 July 1-1959 June 30 (Box 24)
- Ledger, Periodicals/serials, 1940-1942 (Box 24)
- Ledger, Catalog Dept. statistics, 1935 July 1-1942 June 30 (Box 24)
- Ledger, Catalog Dept. statistics, 1942 July 1-1948 June 30 (Box 24)
- Treasure Room Card Files #000-999 (Box 25)
- Bookplates, 1981-1997, undated; 0.25 Linear Feet (Box 26)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes example bookplates, bookplate specifications, bookplate procedures, and some notes. Covers both special fund and alumni bookplates.
- Special Collections in Perkins System, 1992 and 1996, Disk image derived from 3.5" floppy disk. Approximately 1.4 MB, 2 files.
- Personal gifts, inactive, 1980-1990 (Box 27)
- Individual gifts, 1960s-1970s (Box 28)
- Personal gifts, 1990-1993 (Box 29)
- Institutional Gifts, A-O, 1980- (Box 30)
- Institutional Gifts, P-Z and foreign, 1980- (Box 31)
- Gifts in Kind, 1997-2003; Book Plates L-Z; Jantz Collection (Box 32)
- Bright Collection manuscript inventory, undated (Box 33)